時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
에도토피아를 향한 여행을 계속하는 무사시는 쿠사리가마를 사용하는 바이켄과 만나 대전했다.
Musashi had a match against Baiken, the user of kusarigama, during the trip to Edotopia.
처음 보는 쿠사리가마의 위력의 대단함에 한결같던 무사시도 쩔쩔, 고전을 면치 못한다.
In front of the might of kusarigama that he saw for the first time, Musashi was flustered and had a hard fight.
그러나 우정이 트었다. 그리고 에도토피아의 무예 대회에서 재회를 단단히 약속하고 떠났다.
But after all, a new friendship has born. Musashi has promised to meet him again in the martial arts competition, and left.
악의 한조, 살며시 다가오오
Evil Hanzō Creeps
한조 님, 기다리셨습니다.
Thank you for waiting, Lord Hanzō.
그래, 마중 수고했다, 젠조.
Right. I appreciate you for greeting me, Zenzō.
한조
Hanzō
그럼, 예의 물건은?
Now, where is the thing?
예, 이 안에 있습니다.
Yes, it is inside here.
이것입니다.
This is it.
그렇군. 훌륭한 등급이군.
I see. They seem to be perfect.
어떻게 해서라도 밖으로 알려지지 않게 해라.
Do not let any information about this place leak.
예.
Got it.
이것만 있으면 천하는 나, 한조의 것.
With this, the world is in my hands.
그 쯤 무사시는 코지로를 마음에 두고 있으면서도, 애도 코테츠를 허리에 차고 쭉 에도토피아를 향해 가고 있었다.
Meanwhile, having Kojirō in mind, Musashi was heading to Edotopia, carrying Kotetsu, his beloved swords, on his waist.
저건 코지로!
That must be Kojirō!
기다리시오!
Wait-dasu!
뭔가 소생에게 볼 일이?
Do you have anything to say to me?
아니, 아니, 그게, 다른 사람이었소. 실례했소.
No, no, uh, that is, I was looking for a different person-dasu. Excuse me-dasu.
뭐야, 얘?
What's up with this guy?
젠조인가.
Is it Zenzō?
-예.
-말해라.
-Yes.
-Speak.
며칠 전, 호조인 도장에 경찰 장관 주베가 나타났다 합니다.
A few days ago, it is told that Jūbē, the police chief, stopped by at Hōzōin Dōjō.
주베가? 그 놈... 제국의 동세를 정탐하는 역이 아닐 터.
Jūbē? That bastard... He is not supposed to be a spy investigating across the state.
내탐꾼인 내 임무를 넘보고 손톱끝으로 다룰 생각을 하다니.
How dare he tries to take over my role?
그러나 이런 때, 그런 곳에 주베가 나타났다는 것은 설마 그 금광...
But it is possible that Jūbē appeared in that place because of the gold mine...
당황하지 마라. 실수는 없다. 그쪽은...
Don't be flustered. There is no mistake. And for you...
누구냐!
Who is there?!
수상한 놈이다! 잡아라!
Spies! Get them!
이대로는 함께 잡힌다. 너라도 달아나라!
We're going to be caught like this. Run away by yourself!
그럴 수는 없다! 뭔 생각인가?
I shall not! Why would you say that?
우리가 함께 잡히면 한조의 음모를 누가...
If we get caught together, who will expose Hanzō's plot?
자. 빨리 이걸 주베 님께!
Take this to Jūbē right away!
뭔가 있다!
Something's over there!
넌 그쪽을 찾아봐라! 난 저 넘어를 보겠다.
You go look that way! I'll check over that side.
내겐 신경쓰지 마라. 서둘러라!
Forget about me. Hurry!
찾았다!
Found him!
미안하다.
Appreciated.
멈춰라!
Freeze!
그 쯤 코지로는 무사시를 전혀 신경쓰지 않고 쭉 에도토피아를 향하고 있었다.
Meanwhile, Kojirō was heading to Edotopia, and Musashi was nowhere to be found in his thoughts.
무슨 일인가, 대체?! 정신 차려라!
What happened? Wake up!
주, 주베 님께...
Bring this to Jūbē...
어이! 괜찮나! 어이!
Hey! Are you alright? Hey!
비둘기?
Pigeons?
주베에게?
To Jūbē?
뭘 가지고 웅성대오?
What are you all talking about-dasu?
죽은 걸까...
Is it dead?
안 움직이네.
It's not moving.
-비둘기!
-응, 상처를 입고 저 나무 아래에 떨어져 있었어.
-A pigeon!
-Yeah, it was under that tree injured.
상처를? 그럼 빨리 돕지 않으면 불쌍하오.
Injured? We must help that pitiful thing in that case-dasu.
하오?
dasu, you say?
그런 말을 해도 우리는 카라쿠리 새는 어떻게 못 해.
Even if you say so, we can't do anything about a karakuri bird.
아, 그런 거라면 내게 맡기시오!
You can leave that to me-dasu!
얼마 줄 거야?
How much are you going to pay us-dasu?
얼마라니, 주운 거 아니오?
How much? Didn't you say you picked this up-dasu?
아, 그래라! 그럼 어딘가에 버리러 가자!
Oh, I get it! Then let's go throw it away at somewhere else!
쩨쩨하긴!
So stingy!
-가자.
-아, 멈추시오!
-Let's go.
-Hey, stop-dasu!
거참, 최근 아이들은 방심할 수가 없소...
Man, kids nowadays are so sneaky-dasu...
자! 이 정도면 만족하오?
Here! Are you satisfied-dasu?
-이제 산 것이오!
-이오!
-You bought it-dasu!
-dasu!
이것 참...
Man.
자, 어쨌든 한번 보겠소.
Anyway, let me take a look-dasu.
와, 대단한 상처이오...
That's a big wound-dasu.
어?
Huh?
뭣이오, 이것은?
What is this-dasu?
뭐요!
What-dasu?!
참 비겁하오!
How cowardly-dasu!
내게 무슨 원한이 있는 것이오!
What do you have against me-dasu?!
나중에 꼭 치료해 줄 테니까 여기 있소!
I'll come back later to treat you, so stay here-dasu!
젠장, 뭔 일이오!
Damn, what's going on-dasu?!
누구시오! 왜 날 노리시오!
Who are you-dasu?! Why are you after me-dasu?!
무사시가 왜 닌자들에게...
Why are ninjas chasing Musashi?
설마 조금 전 닌자를 무사시가 죽이기라도 한 것인가?
Is it possible that Musashi killed that other ninja just before?
발 빠른 놈!
What swift rat!
-잡아라!
-어이!
-Catch him!
-Right!
끈질긴 놈들이오...
What persistent bastards-dasu...
어째 내가 이런 상황에 처하게 됐소...
What did I wrong to get in this situation-dasu...
놈들, 설마 이걸...?
Are they possibly looking for this...?
무사시 놈, 어떻게든 추격자를 따돌린 모양이구나.
It seems that Musashi has managed to get away from pursuers.
그래도...
But yet...
좋소, 이제 괜찮을 것이오.
Right, you're going to be fine-dasu.
다시 날 수 있게 될 것이오!
You'll be able to fly again-dasu!
역시 이것도 돌려주는 게 좋겠소...
Maybe I should better return this-dasu.
잠깐!
Wait!
너, 너는!
Yo- you are!
코지로!
Kojirō!
뭔 짓이오!
What are you doing-dasu?!
이 비둘기의 주인하고 죽은 자하고 상관있는 듯 하구나.
It seems that the owner of this dove and the dead are somehow related.
어쨌든 이것이 주베와 관계가 있을 듯 하다.
Anyway, this seems to be has something to do with Jūbē.
주베 씨하고?
With Jūbē?
이건...
This...
어쩌면 무언가의 부호.
Possibly, a code of something.
아니, 글자를 숨긴 밀서일지도.
Or a secret message using steganography.
밀서이오?
A secret message-dasu?
그렇다. 읽어보면 네가 몹시 노려진 이유도 알게 될 것이다.
Right. We should know the reason you were chased by reading this.
어라, 이것은!
Look at this!
글자이오!
It's a character-dasu!
이, 이건 대체!
What's going on here?!
그렇군, 이런 장치였군!
So I see how this device works.
꽤 잘 되어 있다. 비치는 것은 여기에 적혀 있던 글자다.
It's pretty well done. The characters written inside are getting projected.
왠지 읽혀지지 않소...
I can't read for some reason-dasu...
내가 읽겠다.
I will read.
이것은 바늘구멍 사진기를 응용한 것이다.
This is an application of the mechanism behind a pinhole camera.
핀홀 카메라라고 불려, 렌즈 대신 작은 구멍을 이용한, 말하자면 카메라의 고선조격이다.
It's as if an ancestor of the modern cameras, using a small hole instead of a lens.
"두 개의 얼굴을 가진 악당, 한조의 정체를 여기에 적는다."
"Hanzō, a villain with two faces, shall be exposed here."
한조? 누구이오?
Hanzō? Who is it?
나도 잘은 모르지만 이하(伊賀) 닌자의 수장으로써 제너럴 이에야스 막부의 밀정이라고 들었다.
Not that I know well, but I heard that he is the head of the Iga ninjas, working as an official spy under General Ieyasu.
그럼 날 쫒은 건 그 밀정이오?
Then was that spy chasing me-dasu?
아니. 아닌 것 같다. 한번 봐라.
No. I don't think so. Take a look for yourself.
"이 남자, 막부의 밀정으로써 지팡구국의 치안을 지키는 장군이면서 실은 뒤에서 다이묘 간 싸움을 붙여
"This man is a general who maintains public peace and order as an official spy,"
"but yet he makes daimyos fight against each other from behind,"
이 세상의 치안을 어지럽히는 일을 이어왔습니다."
"continuing his practice of stirring up trouble."
"게다가 이만큼이나 신고하지 않고 각지의 금광을 소유하는 것은 분명히 막부를 전복시키려는 것."
"Moreover, owning many gold mines across the state without reporting can only mean to overthrow the shogunate."
"자신이 지팡구국의 막후 조종자로써 군림하고자 한다는 증거입니다."
"It is the proof that he is scheming to reign over Jipangu State as the shadow shogun."
"다음은 금광의 위치입니다. 주베 님의 결단을 바랍니다."
"Following is the location of gold mine. Waiting for the decision from Jūbē."
번거로운 놈이오...
That's one troublesome guy-dasu...
한조의 마의 손이 다가온다. 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Hanzō's evil hands are approaching. Wait for the stormy latter half!
사정을 알았지만 말려들고 싶지는 않다.
While I got the situation, I do not want to be involved.
무슨 말이오?
What are you saying-dasu?
알아채지 못했나, 무사시!
Didn't you get it, Musashi?!
코지로!
Kojirō!
생명을 소홀히 여기지 마라! 다시 만나자!
Do not spend your life for nothing! See you again!
기다리시오, 코지로!
Wait for me, Kojirō!
따라오지 마라! 둘로 나뉘어 위기를 모면해라! 다른 길로 돌아가라!
Do not follow me! Divide up to two and escape this situation! Change your path!
그런 말을 해도 혼자 달아날 수는 없소!
Whatever you say, I cannot run away by myself-dasu!
그럼 내가 건너로 가겠다!
Then I'll go that way instead!
기다리시오!
Wait for me-dasu!
뭣이오?
Wh- what the-?!
우리하고는 어떤 관계도 없다. 비켜라!
We have nothing to do with that. Move away!
뭐요?
What the-?!
이런 것에는 당하지 않소!
I won't fall for that-dasu!
젠장이오!
Oh no-dasu!
젠장! 이렇게 됐다면 익히든 태우든 원하는 대로 하시오!
Dammit! Cook, throw into a fire, or do whatever you want-dasu!
벌써 저런다. 왜 녀석은 단세포인 거냐!
He already gave up. What simpleton he is!
거기까지다!
That's as far as you go!
칼을 내려놓아라! 안 놓으면 생명은 없다!
Put down the sword! Or he's as good as dead!
역시 원하는 대로 하는 건 싫소!
Okay, I wouldn't like if they do whatever they want-dasu!
나하고는 상관없는 일이다!
I have nothing to do with this!
일단, 이 녀석은 무엇도 가지고 있지 않다. 죽여봤자 소용없다!
First, that guy does not have anything. Even if you kill, you won't get a thing!
무, 무슨 무책임한 소리를!
How irresponsible he is!
뭐, 너희들 직성 풀릴 때까지 알아보면 알게 되겠지.
Well, you might understand if you investigate as much as you want.
멈춰라! 달아나는가!
Stop right there! You shall not run away!
이, 이건!
Wh- what the...
젠장, 코지로 놈, 달아났소!
Damn... Kojirō ran away-dasu!
어쩔 수 없지. 어쨌든 퇴각이다.
It's no use. Retreating for now.
이 녀석이라도 있으면 어떻게든 되겠지. 충분히 알아볼 테니까.
At least we'd be able to find something out from this guy. We'll find out in plenty.
이거 놓으시오!
Hey! Untie me!
활기찬 사내자식이군.
What a lively boy.
너는!
You!
이하 닌자 군단 수장, 한조! 그보다도 그렇게 날뛰어도 괜찮을까, 꼬맹아.
Head of Iga Ninja Force, Hanzō! But first, would you be okay to act violently, you brat?
네 발 아래에는 지뢰가 깔려 있다. 균형을 잃으면 바로 떨어지겠지.
There are mines under your feet. If you lose balance, you'll fall right away.
자! 밀서는 어디 있나!
Now! Tell me where the secret message is!
난 밀서 따위 가지고 있지 않소!
I don't have any secret message-dasu!
하지만 비둘기에는 없었다. 어디에 숨겼나!
But it wasn't in the pigeon. Where did you hide the message at?
모르는 것은 모르는 것이오!
I don't know what I don't know-dasu!
좋다. 어디까지 그 고집이 갈지 보여줘 보아라.
Alright then. Let's see when your stubbornness goes away.
-네가 떨어지는 동안 그 장치는 자연을 따른다.
-비겁하오! 난 아무것도 모르오!
-As you slowly fall, that device will follow law of nature.
-You're cowardly-dasu! I know nothing-dasu!
살고 싶다면 그 전에 숨긴 곳을 밝혀라.
If you want to live, you shall reveal the location you hid the message.
그런 걸 하면 밀서는 찾을 수 없소!
If you keep doing this, you won't be able to find the secret message-dasu!
상관없다. 산 증인은 하나 더 있으니까.
It doesn't matter. There is another living witness.
자. 그 동안 한가로이 기다리고나 있을까.
Now, let us wait with leisure meanwhile.
-잘 보고 있어라.
-살려주시오!
-Keep an eye on him.
-Help me-dasu!
왜 내가 이런 꼴에 처해야 하오!
Why must I be in this situation-dasu?!
그래! 코지로다!
That's it! Kojirō!
그렇소! 코지로가 달아난 탓이오!
That's it-dasu! It's all because Kojirō ran away!
코지로 개새끼!
Kojirō's an idiot!
고통스럽소, 비겁자!
I'm suffering, you coward!
더 말하면 안 살려준다.
One more word and I'm not saving you.
코지로! 어느 순간에...
Kojirō! When did you...
연기 속에서 갈아입었다. 너 같은 녀석이라도 없으면 허전하니 말이지.
I changed my clothes in the smoke. Even if it's you, I would miss you should you cease to be.
자! 달아나자!
Now! Let's run away!
탈출 성공! 빨리 이 집에서 나가오!
Escape success! Let's hurry and get out of this mansion-dasu!
멍청하긴. 적이 있는 곳에서는 내 칼만으로는 무리다.
Idiot. When there are enemies everywhere, my sword alone isn't enough.
네 칼도 찾아야 한다!
We must find your sword too!
뭣이오, 이건?
What is this?
가짜 맹장지다.
A fake sliding screen.
내 코테츠!
My kotetsu!
묘하군... 추적자의 기미가 없다.
Strange... There are no sign of chasers.
분명 한조 놈이 그새 자버린 바람에 깨닫지 못하는 것일 테오.
Hanzō must have fallen asleep, not realizing that we escaped-dasu.
그렇다면 괜찮겠지만... 어쨌든 서두르자!
I hope so, but let's hurry up for now.
멍청한 놈. 그저 달아나게 두었다 생각하나.
Idiots. You shall not simply run away.
밀서의 소재를 알게 될 쯤에 천천히 죽여 주겠다.
When I get to know where the secret message is, I'll kill you slowly.
뭐? 그 밀서, 에도토피아의 주베 님께 전달한다고?
What? Are you saying that you're going to deliver that secret message to Jūbē in Edotopia?
그렇소. 한조같은 극악한 자는 용서할 수 없소!
Right. An atrocious villain like Hanzō is unforgivable-dasu!
그래도 말이지,
But still...
아, 잠깐!
Hey, stop!
좋소.
Good.
이것으로 한조 일당도 끝장이오!
With this, Hanzō's gang will meet its end-dasu!
아! 멈추시오!
Hey! Stop!
너, 너는!
You- you must be...!
잘 받았다. 가라!
It's ours now. Go!
젠장, 너무 재빠르오!
Damn, they are too quick-dasu!
녀석들, 우리를 쫒아왔어!
Those guys followed us!
밀서를 빼앗겼소!
They took the message-dasu!
내버려둬라! 이 이상 둘러싸이는 것은 사양이다!
Forget it! I refuse to be involved more than this!
그런 말을 해도!
Even if you say so...
해냈소.
We did it-dasu.
어쩌면 좋소?
What should we do-dasu?
딱히 방법이 있을까보냐! 별 방법이 없다!
Like I know! We just run!
이것이오.
This is it-dasu.
끝장이다!
I'll finish you!
무사시!
Musashi!
돌려주겠소!
Take it back-dasu!
이 애송이들이...
You damned brats...
이 원한은 꼭 갚아주겠다!
I will have revenge on you!
즉각적으로 적의 무기를 이용하는 것은 너 치고는 훌륭했다.
Thinking to use your enemy's weapon in a nick of time is praiseworthy even for you.
그럼, 다시 갈라질까.
Then let's separate from now on.
나하고의 승부가 남아있소.
You still have a match against me-dasu.
너하고 같이 있으면 제대로 되는 게 없으니 말이지.
You know, with you, nothing goes alright.
게다가, 나도 이런 편리한 것을 가지고 있다.
And also, I also have some convenient stuff.
안녕이다!
Farewell!
바보 놈.
Idiot.
비겁하오!
That was cowardly-dasu!
젠장, 코지로!
Damn you, Kojirō!
어라, 배가 고파서 똑바로 설 수가 없소...
Huh, I'm too hungry to stand up straight-dasu...
이렇게, 한조의 마의 손은 피해갔지만 그 무서운 음모를 밝히는 밀서를 잃어버렸다.
In this way, he managed to evade the evil hands of Hanzō, but he lost the secret message revealing his fearsome plot.
배가 고파 힘이 들어, 무사는 먹지 않아도 긍지많은 높다지만 갈 길은 먼 무사시였다.
He was too tired and hungry. A starved swordsman still has high spirits, but Musashi wasn't quite there yet.
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
마음껏 먹고 마셨소. 게다가 용돈까지 벌 수 있어서
I've ate and drink as much as I wanted-dasu. Moreover, because I could earn money,
나, 카츠조 일가를 돕게 되었소만,
I decided to help Katsuzō family-dasu,
역시 공짜보다 비싼 것은 없다고 다들 그러오.
but as everyone says, there's no such thing as a free lunch-dasu.
이 무슨, 형제의 약속을 맺은 이시마츠 씨가 있는 지로치오 일가하고 싸우게 되고 말았소.
A twist of fate? I have to fight against Jirochiō family where Ishimatsu, who promised with me to be brothers, is in-dasu.
다음 이야기! 사내 이시마츠, 우정이 지다
Next story! A Man Ishimatsu, Friendship Falls-dasu.
질풍노도의 우정으로 우시오!
Cry by the stormy friendship-dasu!
다음 이야기
사내 이시마츠
우정이 떨어지오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
A Man Ishimatsu
Friendship Falls
Look forwards for it!